# Mohamed Moustafa

### Software Engineer

(updated resume at <a href="https://fairewinds.ca">https://fairewinds.ca</a>)

Canadian living in Utrecht,
Netherlands

mti.moustafa@gmail.com

+31 6 29 27 47 18 +1-519-897-9137

Twitter: <u>@mtimoustafa</u>

🌎 GitHub: <u>@mtimoustafa</u>

LinkedIn: <u>@mtimoustafa</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a full-stack software engineer with 6 years of experience in SaaS-based platforms and microservice architectures. I am proficient in front-end development and champion accessibility and usability. In the future, I aspire to become a technical lead. In my free time, I love to play music, read, and work on hobby coding projects.

**SKILLS** 

UI frameworks

Design systems

Web acessibility

Microservice architecture

Containerised deployment

Customer-facing

experience

**TECH STACK** 

Ruby / Ruby on Rails

Javascript / Vue.js

HTML / CSS / SCSS

Docker / Kubernetes

MySQL / PostgreSQL

AWS

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## SENIOR BACK-END ENGINEER

MARCH 2022 - CURRENT

Livestorm

Paris, France (Remote)

- Coordinated with Infrastructure team to set up new "job manager" microservice using AWS, Kubernetes, and Terraform.
- Maintained, refactored, and documented public-facing API layer in a squads team setting, using Ruby on Rails and Swagger.
- Implemented new features for the application dashboard UI, using Vue.js, GraphQL and Apollo.

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

AUGUST 2021 - FEBRUARY 2022

**Springest (now Studytube)** Amsterdam, Netherlands

- Implemented and maintained core features in a monolith architecture, with a full-stack scope, in Ruby on Rails and Vue.js.
- Assisted in refactoring core "Course Listing" back-end model design.
- Researched containerizing main monolith application into Docker to streamline its communication with other already-containerized services.

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

**APRIL 2017 - JULY 2021** 

#### Vidyard

Kitchener, Ontario, Canada

- Maintainer of key platform microservices, written in Ruby on Rails and Vue.js.
   Responsible for code reviews, refactoring and bugfixing, deploys, and mentorship.
- Maintainer and guild lead of front-end design system in Vue.js. The guild consisted of 6+ engineers, designers, and QAs, and governed future goals and maintainership.
- Responsible for upgrading major parts of the platform to WCAG AA accessibility standards. Mentor for co-workers on how to develop for accessibility.
- Led a project to create a new search feature. Refactored RESTful API endpoints and improved the existing ElasticSearch implementation.
- Refactored a stand-alone microservice to use Docker, Kubernetes, Skaffold, and Vidyard OAuth gear, in order to integrate it into our development environment.
- Improved Vidyard Chrome Extension features and UI, in React.js.
- Interviewed 20+ developer candidates, from interns to senior developers.

Full work experience available on LinkedIn

#### **EDUCATION**

### UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

2011 - 2016

Waterloo, Ontario, Canada

BASc. with Honours, Computer Engineering, Co-operative Program

**Relevant Courses** 

- Operating Systems and Systems Programming
- Cooperative and Adaptive Algorithms
- Fundamentals of Computational Intelligence

#### **CONFERENCES**

- VueConf Toronto (2019, 2020)
- #a11yTO Accessibility Toronto (2019)
- University of Guelph Accessibility Conference (2018, 2019)

#### **INTERESTS**

#### LANGUAGES

English (native)

Arabic (native)

German (basic)

Dutch (basic)

#### INTERESTS

- Member of Vidyard's diversity+inclusion & wellness committees.
- Volunteer at Vidyard's community initiatives.
- I like to work on small coding projects, including a sync tool between financial tools, running Minecraft in Docker, and a crochet project tracker.
- I play the guitar, bass and piano & experiment with music programs like Ableton and FL Studio.
- I like to read sci-fi and self-improvement books.